Oneida Community Collection
Oneida Community Collection
- Manuscripts and personal papers
  - Hinds, William Alfred, 1857-1896; undated
    - Correspondence (Box 48)
      1877 F 2 to Tirzah C. Miller
      Ap 26 to Mary Louise Prindle Jl 1 to Mary Louise Prindle
      1878 Jl 27 to Mary Louise Prindle
      1879 Ap 4 to Mary Louise Prindle
      Je 4 to Mary Louise Prindle
      Je 13 to Mary Louise Prindle
      1880 My 18 to Mary Louise Prindle
      D 18 to Directors of Oneida Community Limited
      1884 N 30 to Mary Louise Prindle
      1890 N 11 to James W. Towner
      1894 Je 3 to Judge G. A. Forbes -- in George Campbell file
      1896 N 11 to Elliot Hinds
      D 17 to Elliot Hinds
      undated to Mary Louise Prindle
      [no year] Mr 8 to Mary Louise Prindle
    - Legal papers (Box 48)
      'A plan that will feed the goose that lays the golden eggs' (1879?)
      Papers relating to the Yakima Irrigating and Improvement Co.
      Articles of Agreement (1881) between J. Hawley, F.A. Marks, William A. Hinds, R.B. Hawley, E.S. Nash, and C.A. Reid re: California land investments
      Wage attachment (1895) to 0.C.L. by Frederick Simmens
    - Writings, Miscellaneous correspondence, drafts on Oneida Community for entry in Schaff-Hertzog Cyclopedia (Box 48)
  - Hinds, William Alfred - "American Communities" collection
    - Biographical materials (Box 49)
    - Scrapbook of Circular articles (Box 49)
    - Outgoing correspondence (Box 49)
      1885-1887 Letterpress copybook
      A-Z
      Unidentified
    - Miscellaneous writings/fragments (Box 49)
    - Clippings (Box 49)
    - Incoming correspondence
      - A-F (Box 50)
      - Frankland, Frederick W., writings, correspondence, clippings (Box 50)
      - G-H (Box 51)
      - Harman, Moses (Box 51)
      - I-Z (Box 51)
    - Periodicals (Box 51)
      The Commons
      Freedom
      Humanity
      The Inner Voice
      The Kingdom of Heaven
      The Malthusian
      Money
      The Philosopher
      Rel ecopol
      Social Unity
      The Sociologist
      The True Life
      World's Advance Thought
    - Miscellaneous printed material (Box 51)
    - Communities
      - Adonai Shomo Corporation, or Community of Futterites (1861-1897), Petersham, Worcester County, MA (Box 52)
      - Altruist Community (1907-1911), Sulphur Springs, Jefferson County, MO (Box 52)
      - Amana Society, or the Society of True Inspiration (1843-1932), Ebenezer, Erie County, NY and Amana, Iowa County, IA (Box 52)
      - Amish (Box 52)
      - Aurora Community (1856-1881), Aurora, Marion County, OR (Box 52)
      - Bayside Communistic Colony, Bayside, Long Island, NY (Box 52)
      - Bethel Community (1844-1880), Bethe, Shelby County, MO (Box 52)
      - Bishop Hill Colony (1846-1862), Bishop Hill, Henry County, IL (Box 52)
      - Brook Farm (1841-1847), West Roxbury, Norfolk (now Suffolk) County, MA (Box 52)
      - Brotherhood of the New Life (1851-1900) (Box 52)
        1851-1853 - Mountain Cove Community, Mountain Cove, VA (now WV)
        1863-1867 - Amenia Community, or Brotherhood of the New Life, Amenia, Dutchess County, NY
        1867-1881 - Brocton Community, or Salem-on-Erie, Brocton, Chautauqua County, NY
        1876-1900 - Fountain Grove Community, Fountain Grove, Sonoma County, CA
      - Buena Vista CoLony, or Great Western Co-operative Home-Building Association (1901?-1919), Buena Vista, CO (Box 52)
      - Celesta (1863-1864), Celesta, Sullivan County, PA (Box 52)
      - Christian Commonwealth Colony (1896-1900), Commonwealth, Muskogee County, GA (Box 52)
        Right Relationship League, Chicago, IL
        "The Social Gospel"
      - Christian Cooperative Association (1898-1902?), Clay Center, KS (Box 53)
      - Christian Social Association (1899-1904), Sarona, WI (Box 53)
      - Civic Brotherhood Church, Washington, DC (Box 53)
      - Colorado Cooperative Company (1894-1910), Nucla, Montrose County, CO, "The Attrurian" (Box 53)
      - Co-operative Association of America (1900-1906?), Lewiston, ME (Box 53)
      - Co-operative Brotherhood, or Burley Colony (1898-1908), Burley, Kitsap County, WA, "The Co-operator" (Box 53)
      - Co-operative Christian Federation (1902), Christadelphia, Benton County, OR (Box 54)
      - Cooperative Commonwealth of Idaho (1898?) (Box 54)
      - Cooperative Industrial Colony (18997-1901?), Milner's Store, Camp Creek, GA (Box 54)
      - Co-operative Union (1901), Ocala FL (Box 54)
      - Cosme Colony (1901-1902?), Paraguay, South America (Box 54)
      - Dansville Sanitarium, See Our Home on the Hillside
      - Davisite Kingdom of Heaven (1867-1881), Walla Walla, WA (Box 54)
      - Doukhobor (1899- ), Transcaucasus, Russia and Manitoba, Canada (Box 54)
      - Ebenezer Society, or the Society of True Inspiration, See Amana Society
      - Eclectic Phalanx, See Virginia Phalanx
      - Eden Society (1907-1908), Baxter Springs, KS (Box 54)
      - Ephrata Colony, or the Solitary Brethren of the Community of the Seventh Day Baptists (1732-1770), Ephrata, PA (Box 54)
      - Equality, or Brotherhood of the Cooperative Commonwealth (later reorganized as Freeland) (1897-1907), Equality, Skagit County, WA (Box 54)
      - Equality Industrial Association (1899?-1901?), Patawattomie County, OK (Box 54)
      - Esoteric Fraternity (1893?-1907), Applegate, CA (Box 54)
      - Fairhope Industrial Association (1895-present), Fairhope, AL, "The Fairhope Courier" (Box 55)
      - Farist Community (18707), Monticello, MN (Box 55)
      - Farmers and Mechanics Co-operative Association (1870?), Missouri (Box 55)
      - Farmers' Incorporated Co-operative Society (1889-1902?), Rockwell, IA (Box 55)
      - Freedom Colony (1897-1905), Fulton, Bourbon County, KS (Box 55)
      - Freeland Association (formerly Equality, or Brotherhood of the Cooperative Commonwealth) (1901-1907), Holmes' Harbor, Whidby Island, WA (Box 55)
      - Friendship Community (1872-1877), Buffalo, Dallas County, MO (Box 55)
      - Fullerites, See Adonai Shomo Corporation
      - Gibbs Cooperative Colony (1901-1907), Gibbs, Santa Cruz County, CA (Box 55)
      - Golden Life Community (1907), Independence, MN (Box 55)
      - Gospel Trumpet Publishing Co., Moundsville, WV (Box 55)
      - Great Western Co-operative Home-Building Association, See Buena Vista Colony
      - Harmony Co-operative Industrial Association (1906?), East Assiniboia, Canada (Box 56)
      - Harmony Society (1805-1814), Harmony, Butler County, PA (Box 56)
      - Harris, Thomas Lake, See Brotherhood of the New Life
      - Helicon Home Colony (1906-1907), Englewood, NJ (Box 56)
      - Holy Band (1903?), Maysville, Brown and Adams counties, KY (Box 56)
      - Holy Rollers (Box 56)
      - Home Colony, See Mutual Home Association
      - Home Employment Co-operative Company (1894-ca. 1906), Long Lane, MO (Box 56)
      - Home Industrial College (1901), Devers, Liberty County, TX (Box 56)
      - Hopedale Community, or Fraternal Community No. 1 (1842-1867), Hopedale, MA (Box 56)
      - House of David (1903-1928), Benton Harbor, MI (Box 56)
      - Hutterite communities (Box 56)
        See also Mennonite and Moravian communities
      - Icarian Community (1847-1895), Nauvoo, IL and Iowa (Box 56)
      - Industrial Brotherhood (18987), ME (Box 56)
      - Industrial College, See Home Industrial College
      - Jackson, James, See Our Home on the Hillside
      - Jerusalem, or the Society of Universal Friends (1788-1820), Jerusalem, NY (Box 56)
      - Kaweah Co-operative Colony (1885-1891), Tulare County, CA (Box 56)
      - Kinderfarm, See Ozark Kinderfarm
      - Koreshan Unity - Estero (1894-present), Estero, Lee County, FL (Box 57)
      - Labadist Colony (1683-1727), Cecil County, MD (Box 57)
      - Labor Exchange Colony, See Freedom Colony
      - League of Brotherhoods (1900), Syracuse, Onondaga County, NY (Box 57)
      - Le Claire Village (1890-19187), Edwardsville, IL (Box 57)
      - Life Culture Society (1904), Los Angeles, CA (Box 57)
      - Martha's vineyard Cooperative Colony (1906?), Vineyard Haven, MA (Box 57)
      - Mennonite & Moravian communities (Box 57)
      - Model City Colony (1899?), St. Joseph, MI (Box 57)
      - Mutual Home Association, or the Home Colony (1898-1921), Carr Inlet, WA (Box 57)
      - National Cash Register Co. (Dayton, Oh.) (Box 58)
      - New Jersey Cooperative Association (1901-19047), Campgaw, Bergen County, NJ (Box 58)
      - Newllano Co-operative Colony (1917-1938), Newllano, Vernon Parish, LA (Box 58)
      - Niksur Co-operative Association (1899), Lawrence (now Wahkon), Lake Mille Lacs, MN (Box 58)
      - Northampton Association of Education and Industry (1842-1846), Broughton's Meadows (now Florence), MA (Box 58)
      - Oneida Community (1848-1881), Oneida, NY (Box 58)
      - Ora Labora Community, or Christian German Agricultural and Benevolent Society of Ora Labora (1862-1868), Bay Port, MI (Box 58)
      - Our Home on the Hillside, Dansville, Livingston County, NY (Box 58)
      - Owen, Robert (Box 58)
      - Ozark Kinderfarm (1907-1967), Licking, Texas County, MO (Box 58)
      - Rappists, See Harmony Society
      - Reunion Community, or the True Family (1866-1870), Oronogo, MO (Box 59)
      - Right Relationship League, See Christian Commonwealth Colony
      - Rochdale Cooperative Association of Missouri (19007), St. Louis, MO (Box 59)
      - Roycrofters (1900-1915), East Aurora, NY (Box 59)
      - Ruskin, John (Box 59)
      - St. Nazianz Colony (1854-1874), St. Nazianz, Maintowoc County, WI (Box 60)
      - Shaker communities (Box 60)
      - Shalam (1884-1901), Dona Ana, NM (Box 60)
        Selections from Oahspe - 7 pamphlets
        Faithists' calendar
      - Skaneateles Community (1843-1846), Mottville, Onondaga County, NY (Box 60)
      - Snow Hill Nunnery, or Seventh Day Baptist Church of Snow Hill (1798-1870), Snow Hill, PA (Box 60)
      - Social Reformers Cooperative Emigration Society (1843) (Box 60)
      - Society of Women in the Wilderness (1694), PA (Box 60)
      - Southwestern & Western Co-operative Farm, Manufacturing, and Transportation Colony (1901?), Star, ME (Box 60)
      - Spirit Fruit Society (1899-1908), Lisbon, OH and Ingleside, IL (Box 60)
      - Straight Edge Industrial Settlement (1899-1918), New York, NY (Box 60)
      - Theosophists, Point Loma, CA (Box 61)
      - Topolobampo Bay Colony (1884-1894), Topolobampo Bay, Mexico (Box 61)
      - Trappists (Box 61)
      - United Family (1896?), Worcester, MA (Box 61)
      - Vegetarian Colony (1901?), Highland, NY (Box 61)
      - Virginia Phalanx (1845-1850?), Gilmer County, VA (Box 61)
      - Wilkinson, Jemima, See Jerusalem
      - Wisconsin Co-operative Union (Box 61)
      - Wisconsin Phalanx (1844-1850), Ceresco (Ripon), WI (Box 61)
      - Women's Commonwealth, or the Sanctificationists (1874-1906), Belton, TX and Washington, D.C. (Box 61)
      - Zion City (1893-1906?) Chicago and Zion City, IL (Box 61)
      - Zoar, or Society of Separatists of Zoar (1817-1898), Zoar, OH (Box 61)
  - Hobart, Ann Sophronia Bailey (Skinner), 1870-1883; undated (Box 62)
    1870 S 30 to Tirzah C. Miller
    O 16 to Harriet H. Skinner
    1871 Je 13 to Harriet N. Olds
    Je 22 to Harriet N. Olds
    O 27 to Harriet N. Olds
    1873 6 to Tirzah C. Miller
    Mr 5 to Charlotte M. Leonard
    Ap 3 to Charlotte M. Leonard
    1875 F 28 to Tirzah C. Miller
    Mr 5 to Tirzah C. Miller
    Mr 9 to Tirzah C. Miller
    Mr 13 to Tirzah C. Miller
    1876 D 8 to Harriet N. Olds
    D 23 to Harriet N. Olds
    1877 F 14 to Tirzah C. Miller
    F 19 to Mary Louise Prindle?
    F 21 to Tirzah C. Miller
    Ap 22 to Tirzah C. Miller
    1879 Ag 27 to Joseph J. Skinner
    Ag 28 to Joseph J. Skinner
    Ag 31 to Joseph J. Skinner
    S 2 to Joseph J. Skinner
    1883 F 7 to Maud K. Barron
    Mr 3 to Joseph J. Skinner
    Jl 2 to
    [no year] Ag 16 to John F. Sears
    [no year] Ag 16 to Beulah Hendee
    undated to T. [Tirzah C. Miller?]
    undated to William A. Hinds
    undated to Joseph J. Skinner
  - Hobart, Lily, See Sketchbook in Kinsley, Jessie: Writings
  - Hollister, Loren, 1855 (Box 62)
    Ap 16 to Marcus L. Worden
  - Howard, Arthur, 1849-1906 (Box 62)
    File of letters received by Arthur Howard from Harriet Howard, T.R. Noyes, W.A. Hinds, C. Cragin, and others
  - Howard, Harriet, 1859; 1883 (Box 62)
    1859 D 18 to Howard family (copy; original in Amherst College Library)
    1883 Ag 31 to Maud K. Barron
  - Hutchins, Elizabeth, 1876-1882 (Box 62)
    1876 8 letters to Agnes Woolworth
    1878 My 6 to Mary Louise Prindle
    1879 Ja 17 to Mary Louise Prindle
    1882 O 8 to William Hamilton
  - Hutchins, John P., 1867-1885; undated (Box 62)
    1867 School composition: Description of J.H.N. (original mss. + 3 typescript variants)
    1882 My 25 to William A. Hinds
    1885 Mr 11 to William A. Hinds
    undated Class exercise (2 p. typescript)
  - Inslee, Belle, 1884 (Box 62)
    O 30 to Tirzah C. Miller
  - Inslee, Clifton Whatley, 1890s (Box 62)
    Letterhead invoice: Madison C. Agent for the Stearns Bicycles
  - Inslee, Edward P., 1872-1894; undated (Box 62)
    1872 Ag 13 to Tirzah C. Miller
    1876 to James W. Towner
    1877 Je 3 to Tirzah C. Miller ('suppressed')
    Je 16 to 'Dear Friends'
    1878 Je 16 to John Humphrey Noyes
    Je 21 Covenant between John Humphrey Noyes and
    Tirzah C. Miller re: Edward P. Inslee
    Ag 4 to Edwin [Burnham]
    1879 Ja 5 to John Humphrey Noyes
    Mr 12 to John Humphrey Noyes
    1880 Mr 23 to Tirzah C. Miller
    1881 My 24 to Paul B. Inslee
    Ag 7 to the Community
    1884 Ja 28 to Tirzah C. Miller
    Ja 31 to Tirzah C. Miller
    F 12 to Tirzah C. Miller
    Ap 13 to Tirzah C. Miller
    1894 N 10 to William A. Hinds
    undated Photograph of Edward Inslee, Tirzah C. Miller, and child
  - Inslee, William, 1848 (Box 62)
    Speech to Rogers salesmen
  - Inslee, William R., 1872; 1877 (Box 62)
    1872 D 26 to Harriet Matthews
    1877 My 9 to Harriet Matthews Ag 17 to Harriet Matthews
  - Johnson, Sarah E., 1873 (Box 62)
    1873 My 16 to Harriet Matthews
  - Jones, Emma, 1865-1880; undated (Box 62)
    1865 My 10 to Beulah Hendee
    1873 D 8 to Harriet N. Olds
    1879 N 1 to Harriet N. Olds
    1880 Ja 16 to Harriet N. Olds
    Ja 23 to Harriet N. Olds
    undated fragment Joslyn, Charles S.
    1867 5 7 to Hepworth Dixon
  - Joslyn Eunice Y., undated (Box 62)
    Book of manuscript poetry, 4 letters to Marcus L. Worden
  - Joslyn, H. M., 1915 (Box 62)
    Notes made by Hope E. Allen
  - Joslyn, Harriet Eliza, See Allen, Harriet Eliza
  - Joslyn, Sidney, 1875; 1876 (Box 62)
    1875 Mr 23 to Beulah Hendee
    1876 N 24 to Harriet N. Olds
  - Kellog, Charles O., 1879-1894 (Box 62)
    1879 Mr 4 to Mary Louise Prindle
    Mr 20 to Mary Louise Prindle
    Je 15 to Mary Louise Prindle
    1862 Kellogg, Mary Elizabeth
    1882-1894 File of letters to Maud K. Baron
  - Kelly, Annie, 1867-1879 (Box 62)
    1867 Je 23 to G. E. Cragin
    1875 F 21 to Edwin Burnham
    Ap 27 to Edwin Burnham--in G. N. Miller file
    1878 Jl 7 to Mary Louise Prindle
    1879 Ap 5 to Mary Louise Prindle
    O 15 to Mary Louise Prindle
  - Kelly, Dwight, 1892-1893 (Box 62)
  - Kelly, Ida Kate, 1866-1879 (Box 62)
    1866 Jl 29 to Annie Kelly
    1867 Jl 16 to Annie Kelly
    Jl 26 to Annie Kelly
    D 6 to Annie Kelly
    1873 N 16 to Tirzah C. Miller
    1875 Ja 24 to Tirzah C. Miller
    1877 Ap 18 to Annie Kelly
    1879 Mr 3 to Annie Kelly
    Je 19 to Mary Louise Prindle
    N 24 to Annie Kelly
  - Kelly, William G., 1878-1887; undated (Box 62)
    - Correspondence
      1878 My 13 to Mary Louise Prindle
      1886 Ap 30 to Fanny (copy) -- original in T.L. Pitt file
      1887 Ja 16 "Attractive religion"
    - Writings
      Autobiography (63 p.)
  - Kinsley, Albert, 1957 (Box 62)
    Reminiscences
  - Kinsley, Corinna Ackley, 1890-1938 (Box 62)
    1890-1892 File of letters to Maud K. Barron
    1938 D 15 to Constance Noyes Robertson
  - Kinsley, Edith, 1892; 1952,; 1958,; undated (Box 62)
    See also Sketchbook in Kinsley, Jessie: Writings
    1892 O 12 to Dorothy Barron
    N 12 to Dorothy Barron
    1952 'The tulip tree' (essay)
    1958 'Father' (34 pp.)
    undated to Dorothy Barron
  - Kinsley, Jane, 1856-1888; undated (Box 62)
    1856 Ja 12 to Marcus L. Worden
    1878 Je 13 to Mary Louise Prindle
    1888 Mr 26 to James B. Herrick
  - Kinsley, Jessie, 1869-1938; undated (Box 63)
    - Correspondence
      1869 Je 16 'School room'
      1880 My 29 to Charlotte M. Leonard
      1880 S 30 to Beulah Hendee
      1899 Ag 27 to Mr. and Mrs. Hinds
      D 9 to William A. Hinds
      1919 S 3 to Charlotte Leonard
      undated to Charlotte Leonard
    - Writings
      'Memories of youth' (typescript & copy)
      'Reflections on the braidings' by Hope Ackley Owen (copy)
      Bedside book (1938)
      Sketchbook (1872- )
      'Community work' (1933)
  - Kinsley, Josephine, 1894 (Box 63)
    1894 F 26 to Dorothy Barron
  - Kinsley, Margaret (Box 63)
    'Recollections' and note on passage from Pierrepont B. Noyes's My father's house
  - Kinsley, Martin, 1947 (Box 63)
    1947 O 6 Funeral service
  - Kinsley, Myron, 1876-1881; undated (Box 63)
    See also Kinsley, Edith: 'Father'
    1876 D 6 to Tirzah C. Miller
    1880 Ja 15 to 'Sister'
    1881 D 24 to John Humphrey Noyes
    'O.C. food shortage meals'
  - Langstaff, Margaret, undated (Box 63)
    S to ?
    O 22 to Naomi Howard (copy; original in Amherst College Library)
  - Lawton, M.E., 1862 (Box 63)
    Ja 15 to Marcus L. Worden
  - Leonard, Charlotte M., 1867-1888; undated (Box 63)
    - Correspondence
      1867 My 5 to Fanny M. Leonard
      Jl 17 to Fanny M. Leonard
      Jl 22 to Fanny M. Leonard
      Ag 1 to Fanny M. Leonard
      Ag 30 to Fanny M. Leonard
      S 6 to Fanny M. Leonard
      S 26 to Fanny M. Leonard
      O 5 to Fanny M. Leonard
      O 7 to Fanny M. Leonard
      O 8 to Tirzah C. Miller
      O 12 to Stephen R. Leonard
      O 20 to Fanny M. Leonard (signed Flora?)
      D 19 to Fanny M. Leonard
      1869 Ja 28 to Fanny M. Leonard
      F 8 to Fanny N. Leonard
      F 22 to Fanny M. Leonard
      Mr 22 to Fanny M. Leonard
      Ap 8 to Fanny M. Leonard
      Ap 30 to Fanny M. Leonard
      Je 16 to Fanny M. Leonard
      Jl 26 to Fanny M. Leonard
      Ag 10 to Fanny M. Leonard
      S 2 to Fanny M. Leonard
      1871 Ap 23 to Fanny N. Leonard
      1873 My 12 to Fanny N. Leonard
      My 18 to Stephen R. Leonard
      1877 Ja 1 to Charlotte N. Leonard [signed by Wallingford Community members]
      1878 Je 10 to Mary Louise Prindle
      Je 21 to Stevie
      1879 N 17 to Humphrey
      1883 Mr 1 to Humphrey
      Mr 5 to Humphrey
      1884/85? to Harriet H. Skinner
      1888 Mr 7 to Sarah K. Dunn
      Mr 16 to Sarah K. Dunn
      Mr 19 to Sarah K. Dunn
      Mr 28 to Sarah K. Dunn
      Ap 6 to Sarah K. Dunn
      Ap 12 to Sarah K. Dunn
      D 8 to William
      [no year] F 23 to Humphrey
      undated to Abel Easton
    - Writings
      1870-1877 journal (typescript)
  - Leonard, Fanny N., 1855-1901; undated (Box 63)
    - Correspondence
      1855 D 14 to Marcus L. Worden
      1856 Ja 9 to 'Putney Friends'
      Ja 18 to Marcus L. Worden
      Ja 23 to Marcus L. Worden
      1867 My 5 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      My 15 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      My 21 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Jl 10 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Jl 15 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      S 1 to Charlotte M. Leonard
      S 8 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      S 12 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      S 23 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      S 29 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      O 3 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      O 6 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      O 16 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      O 29 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      N 17 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1868 5 2 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      S 28 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      D 5 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1869 Ja 11 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Ap 19 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Ap 22 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Je 13 to Stephen R. Leonard
      Je 21 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Jl 19 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Jl 25 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      S 7 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1871 Ap 13 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      My 4 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      My 10 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1873 Ap 17 to Harriet
      Ap 27 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      My 11 to Harriet H. Skinner
      My 18 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Je 2 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Je 3 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Je 4 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Je 15 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Jl 7 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Jl 9 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Ag 5 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Ag 12 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Ag 24 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      S 15 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      O 5 to Charlotte M. Leonard
      O 11 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      O 15 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      O 18 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      O 20 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      O 31 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      N 9 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      N 30 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1873? to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1875 Mr 2 to Tirzah C. Miller
      Ap 12 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Ap 23 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Je 24 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1876 5 29 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1877 Ap 8 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1878 My 8 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      My 12 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      My 26 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Je 10 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Jl 11 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Jl 26 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1879 Ny 5 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Ny 6 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      My 16 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Ag 25 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      S 28 to Nary Louise Prindle
      O 26 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      N 4 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      N 24 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      N 28 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      D 8 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      D 17 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      D 19 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1880 Ap 4 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      My 7 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Jl 12 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      undated to Ann Eliza
    - Writings
      1851-54 Journal
      1848-86 Commonplace book
      1880-1901 Scrapbook [with extracts of J.H. Noyes's letters and talks]
  - Leonard, John, 1868 (Box 63)
    1868 Sketch of mop wringer (copy)
  - Leonard, Stephen R. (I), 1830-1888; undated
    - Correspondence (Box 63.1)
      183- S.R. Leonard's bookplate (copy)
      1840 Jl 4 to John Humphrey Noyes
      1844 F 27 to Fanny N. White
      1867 O 2 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1872 Ap 1 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Ag 17 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Ag 20 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1873 My 26 to Fanny N. Leonard
      Jl 18 to James B. Herrick
      1875 Ap 21 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1876 Jl 16 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      S 3 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      O24 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1878 My 13 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      Je 9 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1880 Mr 11 to Fanny N. Leonard
      Je 13 to Fanny N. Leonard
      1887 Mr 17 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      1888 Ja 22 to Charlotte N. Leonard
      undated to Charlotte N. Leonard
    - Index of vault documents (Oversize 2)
    - Writings (Box 63.1)
      Recollections (copy)
      Miscellaneous family records (copy)
  - Leonard, Stephen R. (II), 1892-1956; undated (Box 64)
    - Correspondence
      1892 Ja 11 to Dorothy Barron Ja 31 to Dorothy Barron
      Recollections of O.C. members (copy; original in possession of Mary Leonard Beagle)
    - Writings
      'Trees of olden time' in: Cornell Plantations X(3):46-47 (Spring 1954)
      'On the age of trees' in Cornell Plantations XIII(2):21-23 (Winter 1956)
      Octagon buildings of New York state. Rev. ed. Comp. by Ruby N. Rounds... from information and photographs supplied by S.R. Leonard. (Cooperstown, 1954)
  - Lord, Joanna, 1902 (Box 64)
    Journal (18 leaves)